Nathaniel C Napier

Software Engineer

SUMMARY

Detail oriented full stack web developer with a background in analytical sciences. I have a passion for creating digital assets that improve the way people interact with others and the world around them. Experienced in collaborating across teams to accomplish goals and deliver results.

WORK EXPERIENCE

DMPK Research Associate, Senior at Vanderbilt University, Nashville, TN Warren Center for Neuroscience Drug Discovery

August 2017 — Present

- Designed, built, and deployed a full stack web application for scheduling, upkeep, and communication of laboratory equipment. This application is now an integral asset in the day-to-day functioning of the lab.
- Program platforms for assay automation
- Upkeep, repairs, and maintenance of all laboratory equipment within the DMPK lab- most notably MS/MS-LC systems.
- Data analysis and benchwork experimentation.

DMPK Lab Manager (Full Stack Web App) – Allows for intra-laboratory communication from desktop or smartphone. Users can check the current status of lab equipment, as well as schedule time on equipment and request repairs. DMPK Lab Manager serves as a central hub for team members to communicate about projects, instrument status, scheduling, and collaboration- eliminating the need to consult multiple resources.

Teach Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node.js, MongoDB

Research Administrator at Vanderbilt University, Nashville, TN Medical-Image Analysis and Statistical Interpretation Lab

October 2016 — August 2017

- Acquisition and management of data vital to research operations.
- Writing code to compile large datasets from collaborating researchers, laboratories, and data banks.
- Overseeing the design and implementation of projects within the lab.
 Coordinating studies across multiple labs in several states with traveling volunteers.

Forensic Special Chemist, Aegis Sciences Corporation, Nashville, TN

March 2015 — October 2016

• Extraction and purification of analyte from patient sample using various extraction methods. Design and update SOP to improve assays.

Chemist, ESC Lab Sciences, Nashville, TN

May 2014 — March 2015

- Performed digestion of soil, water, sludge, and other environmental samples for analysis via ICP/MS.
- Contamination control and various laboratory maintenance and upkeep.

References available upon request.

CONTACT

931.200.2016

nathanielclarknapier@gmail.com

github.com/ncnapier

linkedin.com/in/nathaniel-napier-bb250380/

SKILLS

HTMI

CSS

JavaScript

React

C#

Python

Node

MongoDB

SQL

OOP

Web Accessibility

EDUCATION

Tennessee Technological University

2010 - 2014

graduated: May 2014

Major: Biochemistry

cum laude